lush.co.uk 2015-09-09

# Privacy Policy | Lush Fresh Handmade Cosmetics

We are Lush Retail Limited (company registration number 03084750) and we are the data controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1988.

This statement discloses the privacy practices and policies for the Lush website. If you have any questions about these practices and policies, please email us at [wecare@lush.co.uk](mailto:wecare@lush.co.uk)

Your personal data will be used for processing and invoicing your order and when dealing with your enquiries and, if you opt in, to send you information about Lush and its products. This may involve processing sensitive personal data about your health that you give to us. 

If you would like to be kept up to date with all the new exciting Lush news, you can opt in for our newsletter and Lush Times! All you have to do sign-up via our website or customer care team and there you have it; you can then confirm that your e-mail address is correct and is the same address you have used to order with.

If you do not want to receive Lush Times or Lush emails anymore please e-mail [wecare@lush.co.uk](mailto:wecare@lush.co.uk) or contact us on +44 (0) 1202 668545. If you would like to change your personal data on our database or you want a copy of the data we hold on file please e-mail [wecare@lush.co.uk](mailto:wecare@lush.co.uk) or call us on +44 (0) 1202 668545.

We may share your information on a confidential basis with our third party providers and group companies. However, don't worry, your data is not publicly available and we will never pass it on to anyone who will plague you with non-Lush marketing stuff. We treat your data as strictly confidential!

The only exceptions are:

  * if you breach our Content Standards as described within our Conditions of Use for example by posting something on our website and we receive a reasonable claim of Intellectual Property infringement (e.g. you have used someone else's picture or song and they complain) or a breach of the right to privacy (eg put up a picture of someone doing something against the public interest) then we may have to pass on your details however we will tell you first unless it is the police asking;

  * if we sell our business or part of our business in which case personal data held about you could be transferred but you would be notified and be given the opportunity to have your data removed.

The data (including any sensitive personal data, such as health related data) that you submit may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or one of our group companies and/or by our group companies' contractors and suppliers. By providing us with your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing and other processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

 **Website Cookies**

Our website uses a few main cookies;

We keep a session cookie which is a small file on our server allowing us to distinguish you from other users, so that we can keep a virtual "basket" of the products you add to your shopping cart.

A second cookie detects whether your browser supports JavaScript, this helps us to deliver the best possible experience online whilst using the Lush website.

We also use [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/), which sets a small cookie file on your computer browser. This cookie stores no personal information about you and will keep a track of how you browse our website. We use this anonymous information to help us further improve the shopping experience on our website.

Some of the pages on Lush.co.uk use content embedded from another website, for example YouTube, you maybe sent cookies from these websites. We don’t actually control these cookies and we would recommend that you visit these third parties for more information about their cookies:

  * [Barclaycard SmartPay](http://www.barclaycard.co.uk/business/smartpay/en#tabbox0) (our payment provider), [YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/) (to view videos), [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/) (to share content) and [NOSTO](http://www.nosto.com/) (provide our trending products, articles and ingredients).

We don't sell the information collected by cookies, nor do we disclose the information to third parties, except where required by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies). We treat your information as sensitive and confidential.

If you continue without changing your settings, we'll assume you are happy to accept all cookies on the Lush website.

If cookies aren’t enabled on your device, it will mean that your shopping experience on our website will be limited to browsing and researching. Unfortunately you will not be able to add products to your basket and buy them.

(Now the lawyer type has left the room, aaargh! You know we will do the right thing and hope you will too.)
